A Guide to the University of Virginia Student Notebooks, 1827-1882
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Student Notebooks 1827-1882
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-22/1/1.841
This collection consists of 80 volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1985 March 5.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains lecture notes taken by students in various classes at the University of Virginia. A hectograph copy of William E. Peters' Latin grammar is also present as are six volumes of lecture notes taken at other schools including Emory and Henry.
Contents List
- University of Virginia
  - Philip St. George Cocke - Notes on the General History of Polybius 1827 (Box 1)
    1
  - Philip St. George Cocke - Chemistry (vol. 1) 1827-1828 (Box 1)
    2
  - Philip St. George Cocke - Chemistry (vol. 2) 1827-1828 (Box 1)
    3
  - William Marshall Ambler - Natural Philosophy (vol. 1) 1831-1832 (Box 1)
    4
  - William Marshall Ambler - Natural Philosophy (vol. 2) 1831-1832 (Box 1)
    5
  - Merit M. Robinson [and Cary Charles Cocke] - Chemistry 1831-1832 (Box 1)
    6
  - John Tayloe Key - Chemistry 1833-1836 (Box 1)
    7
  - Cary C. Cocke - Chemistry 1834 (Box 1)
    8
  - Cary Charles Cocke - Chemistry 1834 (Box 1)
    9
  - John R. Woods - Medicine 1834-1835 (Box 1)
    10
  - Joseph Biddle Wilkinson - Chemistry and French 1835-1836 (Box 1)
    11
  - Charles Randolph Chemistry 1836 (Box 2)
    12
  - Joseph Biddle Wilkinson - Physiology and Richard J. Harrison - Medicine 1836 (Box 2)
    13
  - Blakely J. Williams and Cary C. Cocke - Grammar, Natural Philosophy and Political Economy 1836 (Box 2)
    14
  - A. Maxwell - Chemistry and Physiology 1836-1837 (Box 2)
    15
  - William Raymond McLaws - French Literature and Geography 1837 (Box 2)
    16
  - Charles S. Lewis - Natural Philosophy 1837-1838 (Box 2)
    17
  - Charles S. Lewis - Medicine 1837-1838 (Box 2)
    18
  - Cary Cocke - Bookkeeping 1839 (Box 2)
    19
  - Cary Cocke - Bookkeeping 1839 (Box 2)
    20
  - Cary Cocke - Bookkeeping 1839 (Box 2)
    21
  - Unidentified - Chemistry ante 1843 (Box 2)
    22
  - William Le Roy Brown - Mathematics 1848-1849 (Box 2)
    23
  - David H. Pendleton - Anatomy and Physiology 1850-1851 (Box 2)
    24
  - George H. Dinges - Chemistry 1851-1852 (Box 3)
    25
  - George H. Dinges - Physiology 1851-1852 (Box 3)
    26
  - Thomas L. Yancey - Law 1853-1954 & 1867-1869 (Box 3)
    27
  - J. V. Nash, Edward T. Harrison A. M. C. Duncan, et al. - Mathematics 1853-1856 (Box 3)
    28
  - Don Peters Halsey - Modern History 1854-1856 (Box 3)
    29
  - Thomas L. Yancey - Law 1854 (Box 4)
    30
  - Charles A. Yancey - Accounts 1867-1869 (Box 4)
  - E. B. Smith, Assistant Professor of Mathematics 1855 (Box 4)
    31
  - Don Peters Halsey - Greek 1856 (Box 4)
    32
  - Don Peters Halsey and G. T. Jones - Law, Greek and French 1856 (Box 4)
    33
  - W. Thurmond - Law 1856-1857 (Box 4)
    34
  - James L. Hubard - Law 1856-1857 & 1860-1861 (Box 5)
    35
  - Samuel P. Latané - European History and John Latané 1858-1859 & n.d. (Box 5)
    36
  - George R. Calvert-Law 1857 (Box 5)
    37
  - Philip P. Barbour - Law 1860-1861 (Box 5)
    38
  - Philip P. Barbour - Law 1860-1861 (Box 5)
    39
  - Philip P. Barbour - Law [1860-1861] (Box 6)
    40
  - Philip P. Barbour - Law [pulled items in cf] 1861 (Box 6)
    41
  - John H. Cocke - Latin 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    42
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Anglo Saxon 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    43
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Latin 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    44
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - French 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    45
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - French 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    46
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - French 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    47
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Geometry 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    48
  - William C. Stubbs - Greek, French, Mathematics, German and Surveying in Index Return...by Rev. John Todd...4th ed. 1865-1866 (Box 6)
    49
  - John H. Cocke - French 1866-1867 (Box 6)
    50
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Mathematics & Ugly Club fees 1866-1867 (Box 6)
    51
  - D. C. B. Wilson - Law 1866-1867 (Box 6)
    52
  - John H. Cocke - Latin 1866-1868 (Box 6)
    53
  - John H. Cocke - Mineralogy and Geology 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    54
  - John H. Cocke - Mathematics 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    55
  - F. D. Moore - Law 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    56
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Chemistry (vol. 1) 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    57
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Chemistry (vol. 2) 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    58
  - Peyton H. Skipwith, Jr. - Mineralogy, Geology and Natural Philosophy 1867-1868 (Box 7)
    59
  - John Hartwell Cocke - Law 1868-1869 (Box 7)
    60
  - J. T. Ellyson - Mineralogy and Geology 1868-1869 (Box 7)
    61
  - Francis H. Smith, Professor of Mineralogy and Geology - Lecture Notes 1868-1869 (Box 7)
    62
  - Robert M. Hughes - Literature 1873-1876 (Box 8)
    63
  - Mark B. Winder - Latin and Mathematics 1875-1876 (Box 8)
    64
  - Mark B. Winder - Mathematics 1875-1877 (Box 8)
    65
  - Mark B. Winder - Philosophy, Constitution and Law 1878-1879 (Box 8)
    66
  - Mark B. Winder - Physics 1878-1879 (Box 8)
    67
  - Mark B. Winder - Chemistry 1879 (Box 9)
    68
  - Mark B. Winder - International Law 1879 (Box 9)
    69
  - William Lewis Yancey - Law 1881-1882 (Box 9)
    70
  - William Lewis Yancey - Law 1881-1882 (Box 9)
    71
  - Latin Grammar by William E. Peters, Professor of Latin; hectograph copy published by R. D. Anderson & Bro., 1882 ca. 1882 (Box 9)
    72
  - John Thomas Gibson and David A. Wright - Law n.d. (Box 9)
    73
  - Unidentified - Chemistry and Geology n.d. (Box 10)
    74
- Emory and Henry College and Miscellaneous Schools
  - Cary Charles Cocke while a student in Philadelphia [and James A. Beasley] - Medicine 1837-1838 (Box 10)
    75
  - Cary Charles Cocke (in Philadelphia) - Medicine 1837-1838 (Box 10)
    76
  - Don Peters Halsey, Emory and Henry College - Latin 1853 (Box 10)
    77
  - Don Peters Halsey, Emory and Henry College - Greek, Agricultural Chemistry, Natural Philosophy, Botany and Latin 1853-1855 (Box 10)
    78
  - Don Peters Halsey, Emory and Henry College - Spanish 1854 (Box 10)
    79
  - Manuscript treatise on the disease of the alimentary canal and of the respiratory system, 226 pp. n.d
    80